In this video, I'm going to talk about the Bayesian interpretation of weight
在这个视频中 我们将要讨论权重惩罚的贝叶斯解释
penalties. In the full Bayesian approach, we try to
在完整的贝叶斯方法中
compute the posterior probability of every possible setting of the parameters of a
我们尝试计算模型参数每一个 可能取值点的后验概率
model. But there's a much reduced form of the
但是这里还有一个简化版的贝叶斯方法
Bayesian approach, where we simply say, I'm going to look for the single set of
就是仅仅去寻找一个参数集
parameters that is the best compromise between fitting my prior beliefs about
能够最好地在匹配我们关于参数的先验信息
what the parameters should be like, and fitting the data I've observed.
和匹配观测到的数据之间平衡
This is called Maximum alpha Posteriori learning and it gives us a nice
这叫做最大alpha后验学习
explanation of what's really going on, when we use weight decay to control the
当我们使用权重衰减来控制模型相容性时 这很好地解释了真正发生了什么
capacity of a model. I'm now going to talk a bit about what's
我接下来将要解释一下
really going on, when we minimize the squared error during supervised maximum
当我们最小化 监督最大似然学习的平方误差时
likelihood learning. Finding the weight vector that minimizes
都发生了什么 寻找权重向量来最小化
the squared residuals, that is the differences between the target value and
真实值与模型预测值之间的平方误差
the value predicted by the net, Is equivalent to finding a weight vector
与寻找一个权重向量
that maximizes the log probability density of the correct answer.
来最大化正确答案的对数概率密度 是等价的
In order to see this equivalence, we have to assume that the correct answer is
为了证明这个等价性 我们要先假设正确答案
produced by adding Gaussian noise to the output of the neural net.
是由神经网络的输出值 加上一个高斯噪声来产生的
So the idea is, we make a prediction by first running the neural net on the input
所以想法就是我们从输入用神经网络得到输出
to get the output. And then adding some Gaussain noise.
然后加一些高斯噪声
And then we ask, what's the probability that when we do that, we get the correct
然后我们问 当我们这样做的时候
answer? So the model's output is the center of a
所以模型的输出值是某个高斯分布的中心
Gaussian and what we're interested in is having the target value of high
并且我们对这个高斯分布中 概率最高的取值很感兴趣
probability under that Gaussian because the probability producing the value t,
因为在申请网络输出y的条件下 产生值t的概率
given that the network gives an output of y is just the probability density of t
就是在以y为中心的高斯分布中
under a Gaussian centered at y. So the math looks like this: let's suppose
t点的概率 所以事情就是这样的
that the output of the neural net on training case c is yc and this output is
我们假设神经网络在训练集c上 的输出为yc
produced by applying the weights W to the input c. The probability that we'll get
并且这个输出是通过对输入c应用了 权重W后得出的
the correct target value when we add Gaussian noise to that output yc is given
我们添加高斯噪声后得到正确目标值 的概率
by a Gaussian centered on yc. So we're interested in the probability
由一个以yc为中心的高斯分布决定 所以我们对目标值的分布密度感兴趣
density of the target value, under a Gaussian centered at the output of the
这个分布密度是给定以神经网络的输出 为中心的高斯密度的条件下的条件密度
neural net. And on the right here, we have that
在右边我们有一个以yc为均值 的一个高斯分布
Gaussian distribution, with mean yc. We also have to assume some variance, and
我们同时假设了某个方差的取值
that variance will be important later. If we now take logs and put in a minus
这个方差在之后会很重要 如果我们对式子取负对数
sign, We see that the negative log probability
我们会发现在给定神经网络输出yc的条件下
density of the target value tc given that the network outputs yc, is a constant that
目标值tc的条件分布密度的负对数
comes from the normalizing term of the Gaussian plus the log of that exponential
是一个来自正态分布归一化系数的常数加上
with the minus sign in which is just (tc2 - yc)^2 divided by twice the variance of
负的e的(tc-yc)^2除以两倍方差次幂
the Gaussian. So what you see is that, if our cost
你可以看见
function is the negative log probability of getting the right answer, that turns
如果我们的损失函数是 得到正确答案概率的负对数
into minimizing a squared distance. It's helpful to know that whenever you see
这就变成了最小化一个平方距离 了解以下一点是很有帮助的
a squared error being minimized, you can make a probabilistic interpretation of
当你看到一个平方误差被最小化时 你可以用概率的观点来解释这一切
what's going on, and in that probabilistic interpretation, you'll be maximizing the
并且在这个概率的解释中 你是在最大化一个
log probability under a Gausian. So the proper Bayesian approach, is to
高斯密度的对数 所以这种漂亮的贝叶斯方法
find the full posterior distribution over all possible weight vectors.
就是寻找所有可能取值的权重向量 的整个后验分布
If there's more than a handful of weights, that's hopelessly difficult when you have
如果权重很多的话 那么当你处理非线性网络的时候就很绝望
a non-linear net. Bayesians have a lot of ways of
贝叶斯学者有很多方法
approximating this distribution, often using Monte Carlo methods.
来近似这个分布 通常使用的手段是蒙特卡洛方法
But for the time being, let's try and do something simpler.
从时间角度考虑 让我们做一些更简单的
Let's just try to find the most probable weight vector.
我们仅仅去寻找最可能的 权重向量
So the single setting of the weights that's most probable given the prior
那么关于权重的单一设定就是 给定数据和先验信息是最可能的那个
knowledge we have and given the data. So what we're going to try and do is find
那么我们要做的就是寻找
an optimal value of W by starting with some random weight vector, and then
一个最优的W 这个过程从一个随机的向量开始
adjusting it in the direction that improves the probability of that weight
然后寻找给定数据下 能够提高取该权重可能性的方向
factor given the data. It will only be a local optimum.
这样我们只能得到一个局部的极小值
Now, it's going to be easier to work in the log domain than in the probability
这时候取对数之后问题会变得更好处理
domain. So if we want to minimize a cost, we
如果我们想最小化一个损失函数
better use negative log props. Just an aside about why we maximize sums
我们最好是对他取负对数 这也正是我们为何最大化对数概率的和
of log probabilities, or minimize sums of negative log probs,
或者最小化负对数概率的和
What we really want to do is maximize the probability of the data, which is
我们最后把问题归结到最大化数据的概率
maximizing the product of the probabilities of producing all the target
也就是最大化我们对不同训练情境下
values that we observed on all the different training cases.
得到的观测产生目标值的概率的乘积
If we assume that the output errors on different cases are independent, we can
如果我们假设不同情形下输出误差是独立的
write that down as the product over all the training cases, of the probability of
那么这个就能表示为所有不同情况下
producing the target value, tc, given the weights.
给定权重条件下产生目标值概率的乘积
That is the product of the probability of producing tc, given the output that we're
这也就是在给定网络输出值的条件下 得到tc的概率的乘积
going to get from out network, if we give it input c and it has weights W.
如果我们输入c和权重W的话
The log functions monotonic, and so it can't change where the maxima are.
对数函数是单调的 所以取对数不会改变最大值点
So instead of maximizing a product of probabilities, we can maximize the sums of
所以我们不去最大化概率的乘积 而是去最大化对数概率的和
log probabilities, and that typically works much better on a computer.
这通常在计算机上处理起来更方便
It's much more stable. So we maximize the log probability of the
而且会更稳定 所以我们最大化给定权重
data given the weights, which is simply maximizing the sum over all training cases
产生数据的概率的对数 也就是对所有训练情形来说
of the log probability of the output for that training case, given the input and
给定输入和权重下产生输出的概率 取对数之后的和式
given the weights. In Maximum a Posteriori learning, we're
在最大后验学习中
trying to find the set of weights that optimizes the trade off between fitting
我们总是尝试寻找一些权重 能够最优化拟合先验和拟合数据之间的权衡
our prior and fitting the data. So that's base theorem.
所以这是最基本的定理
If we take negative logs to get a cost, we get that the negative log of the
如果我们取了负对数来得到一个损失函数 那么我们得到的是给定数据后
probability of the weights given the data, is the negative log of the prior term, and
权重向量如此取值的概率之负对数 可以表达成一个先验项对数的相反数
the negative log of the data term, and an extra term.
加上数据项对数的相反数 再加上一个额外的项
So, that last extra term, is an integral overall possible weight vectors.
这就是这个额外项 是对所有可能的权重向量积分后的结果
And so that doesn't affect W. So we can ignore it when we're optimizing
这一项不影响W 所以当对W做优化时 我们可以丢掉这一项
W. The term that depends on the data is the
依赖于数据的那一项
negative log probability is given W, and that's our normal error term.
是给定W下条件概率的负对数 并且这是我们的正态误差项
And then term that only depends on W is the negative log probability of W under
只依赖于W的那一项是先验信息下 W概率的负对数
its prior. Maximizing the log probability of a weight
最大化权重概率的对数
is related to minimizing a squared distance, in just the same way as
与最小化一个平方距离有关
maximizing the log probability of producing correct target value is related
这和最大化产生正确的目标值概率的对数与 最小化平方距离有关一样
to minimizing the square distance. So minimizing the squared weights is
所以最小化平方权重与
equivalent to maximizing the log probability of the weights under a
最小化权重概率的对数是等价的
zero-mean Gaussian prior. So here's a Gaussian.
这个等价性在零均值高斯先验 这样一个条件下成立
It's got a mean zero, and we want to maximize the probability of the weights,
这就是一个高斯分布其均值为零 并且我们想要最大化权重向量的概率
or the log probability of the weights. And to do that, we obviously want w to be
或者说权重概率的对数 为了这么做 我们显然要
close to the mean zero. The equation for the Gaussian is just like
让w接近于均值零 这个高斯分布的表达式就是这样的
this, where the mean is zero so we don't have to put it in.
他的均值是零 所以我们不需要把他放进去
And the log probability of w is then the squared weights scaled by twice the
w概率的对数正是被两倍的方差除
variance, plus a constant that comes from the normalizing term of the Gaussian.
的权重平方加上一个来自高斯分布归一化系数的项
And isn't affected when we change w. So finally we can get to the basing
当我们改变w的时候不会受到影响 所以我们最终得到了
interpretation of weight decay or weight penalties.
权值衰减或者说权重惩罚的解释
We're trying to minimize the negative log probability of the weights given in the
我们尝试最小化给定数据后权重向量概率的负对数
data and that involves minimizing a term that depends on by the turn the weights
这涉及到最小化与权重有关的项
namely how will we shift the targets and determine that depends only on the
也就是说目标值如何改变并且确定下来 仅仅依赖于权重
weights. Is derived from the log probability of the
这来源于给定权重下数据概率的对数
data given the weights, which if we assume Gaussian noise is added to the output of
如果我们假设模型输出有 一个加性的高斯噪声
the model to make the prediction, then that log probability is the squared
那么对数概率是
distance between the output of the net on the target value scaled by twice the
输出值y和t之间距离的平方 除以两倍的方差
variance of that Gaussian noise. Similarly, if we assume we have a Gaussian
类似的 如果我们假设权重的 先验分布服从高斯分布
prior for the weights, the log probability of a weight under the prior is the squared
那么在这个先验下的对数概率就是
value of that weight scaled by twice the variance of the Gaussian prior.
权重值的平方除以两倍的高斯分布之方差
So now let's take that equation and multiply through by two sigma squared D.
让我们写下这个方程 并且等式两边同乘以sigma D的平方
So, we got a new cost function. And the first term, when we multiply through turns
这样我们就得到了一个新的损失函数 并且当我们乘完以后
into simply the sum of all training cases of the squared difference between the
第一项变成了所有输出值与目标值差的平方和
output of the net and the target. That's the squared error that we typically
也就是我们一般在神经网络上 最小化的平方误差
minimize in the neural net. The second term now becomes, the ratio of
第二项就变成了两个方差的比
two variances times the sum of the squares of the weights.
乘以权重值的平方
And so what you see is, the ratio of those two variances is exactly the weight
这样你就能看到 两个方差的比值就是权重惩罚
penalty. So we initially thought of weight
所以我们一开始
penalties as just a number you make up to try and make things work better.
把权重惩罚看作一个你用来 让事情变得更好的一个数
Where you fix the value of the weight penalty by using a validation set.
通过使用验证集 我们可以固定权重惩罚的数值
But now we see that if we make this Gaussian interpretation where we have a
但是我们现在可以看到 如果我们使用了高斯分布的解释角度
Gaussian prior and we have a Gaussian model of the relation of the output of the
也就是说对先验分布以及输出-目标值关系模型 两处的高斯分布假设
net to the target, Then the weight penalty is determined by
那么权重惩罚就是由分布的方差决定的
the variances of those Gaussians. It's just the ratio of those variances.
也就是这两个分布方差的比值
It's not an arbitrary thing at all within this framework.
在这个框架下 其取值并不是随意的 翻译: iChen | 审核: Coursera Global Translator Community